DAMILOLA IBIKUNLE

SENIOR SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

I am a senior scientific officer with 5 years of working experience in research and development within the areas of space and satellite technologies.

I also have over 3 years of professional experience in customer care service and a graduate educational background in Information Security.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

National Space Research and Development Agency (NASRDA)

Jan 2023 - Present

- Responsible for overseeing and managing the instrumentation team within the spacecraft aerodynamics and control department
- Ensuring accurate and adequate measurement and application of all data/apparatus used for a successful satellite design and mission life.
- Member of the team assigned to design and develop customizable Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) tailored for specific purposes.
- Conduct independent research on Space and Satellite Technologies.
- Active member of the Training and Technical Committee within the Nigerian Institute of Space Engineers (NISEng).

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER

National Space Research and Development Agency (NASRDA)

Aug 2018 - Dec 2022.

- Conduct independent and extensive research on control systems for Space and Satellite Technologies.
- Member of the embedded systems team responsible for designing and developing space equipment, including Unmanned Ground Vehicles (UGVs) and Deep Space Antenna Trackers.

CUSTOMER CARE REPRESENTATIVE

Globacom Limited (GLO) Jan 2015 - July 2018

- Providing customers with accurate information about the company's products and services in response to their inquiries.
- Addressing and resolving customer account issues, and escalating them to the relevant channels when required.
- Efficiently updating and maintaining customer account information using a variety of company applications while exhibiting strong multitasking abilities.
- Creating service requests for each customer to facilitate the preparation of comprehensive product and services reports for company analysis.
- Assisting in sales efforts by advising and educating customers about new products and services introduced by the company.

INTERNSHIP - NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC)

SHELL PETROLEUM DEVELOPMENT COMPANY OF NIGERIA - (SPDC ABUJA)
Jul 2011 - Jul 2012

- Offering infrastructure and IT support services.
- Managing and organizing records and manifests for visiting staff and guests.
- Assisting the welfare committee with various company events, including the annual Shell University Scholarship Scheme in Abuja.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.SC)

Information Security
University of Salford Manchester | Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.SC)

Computer Science

University of Lagos Akoka | Sept 2006 - Dec 2010

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Python for Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Microsoft Excel
- HTML/CSS
- Java script

OTHER SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Data Security
- Customer Relationship management
- Risk Assessment

CERTIFICATIONS

IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

IBM Skills Network

Jun 27, 2023

CONTACT



https://damiieibikun.github.io/



https://github.com/Damiieibikun

 \bowtie

damiieibikun@gmail.com

7

+2349082069368



Abuja Nigeria